# Sunil Kumar

sunilkumarsheoran@gmail.com +1-6043674432 linkedin.com/in/sunilkumarsheoran ECS 412, University of Victoria,

Victoria, BC, Canada. V8P 5C2

I am a Master of Computer Science student at the University of Victoria. I have 3 years of software development experience with software product companies. I am seeking co-op opportunities where I can fully utilize my skills for the success of the organization and learn new skills for the cutting edge of technologies in the industry.

## **Education**

M.Sc. in Computer Science Jan 2019 - Expected Dec 2020 University of Victoria, BC, Canada. - 7.33 / 9.0 GPA

Projects: Training a DQN agent for Coinrun (github.com/Unimax/coinrun-dqn-pytorch) and Matchmaking for online multiplayer games (git.io/JenE4).

**B.Tech. in Information Technology** Aug 2010-May 2014 NIT Durgapur, West Bangal, India. - 8.10 / 10.0 CGPA Projects: Collage Study Point Website (git.io/JenEB), Digital Clock on Multisim and Exploration bot.

## **Technical Skills**

- Languages: Java, JavaScript, Python, Golang, PostgreSQL, MySQL, C, C++, PHP, CSS, HTML.
- Tools: Docker, Kubernetes, Office, Adobe Photoshop, gRPC, REST APIs, Git, Google Web Toolkit (GWT), JDBC, Hibernate, OOPs, Data Structures, Deep Learning, Electron, Angular, Eclipse Modeling Framework (EMF), Jasper Report.
- Operating Systems: Linux, Windows

## **Experience**

## Technical Associate / Zillious Solutions, New Delhi, India.

July 2018 - Dec 2018

- Developed an alternative for Java enum reaching to its limit issue causing minimum changes in the application.
- Incorporated support for customizable voucher and integrated multiple payment gateways including *PayTM*, *Razerpay* etc.
- Integrated pre-developed machine learning model into the application for finding duplicate hotels.

#### Software Developer / Drishti-Soft Solutions, Gurugram, India.

June 2014 – Sep 2016

- Awarded with Excellence Award 2016 and won /tmp 2014 (i.e. 10 days 24x7 coding event).
- Majorly worked on Ameyo Report, a GWT based front-end and Jasper based backend; This includes a UI renew, automating the generation of *Transformers*, a data de-normalization component, by using EMF modeling and backend enhancements.
- Created a report scheduler based on Quartz library with support for centralized reporting and graphical reports.
- Increased performance for a large customer's reporting database by 90% using table partition and multicolumn indexes.
- Increased performance of a statics managing component by 60% using soft references based cache for reflective calls.
- Developed a context-aware report designer with the Front-end based on GWT with data populating based on EMF model instances and outputs a proprietary file format (.drxml) which converted by the backend into a jasper-reports based object. It was used to give demos to international customer as a future project.
- Created Magic Numbers: Predicts hardware requirements (CPU, RAM, and HDD) based on customer requirements.
- Automate HDFC collection process. Fresh UI, Integrating HCP for storage, SSO Authenticating server & Centralized Exclusion.
- Part of the Hiring team for the 2016 and 2017 batches. (Question preparation, Interview Rounds and training after hiring).

## Software Developer Intern / Morphing Machines, Bangalore, India.

June 2013 – Aug 2013

- Designed and developed the front-end interface for a research project called 'Development of A Flexible Framework for A Network On Chip'. We wrote a research paper about it (<u>GitHub</u>).
- UI starts with a 4 page Wizard then shows <u>EMF</u> based resulted graph using <u>Graphiti</u> and finally produce a XML for the python written scripts which run and produce <u>VHDL</u> based back-end <u>NOC</u>.

# **Hobbies**

- Video Games (2nd in COBX and Aorus Land 2017 National DOTA 2 tournament, Won Playtonia & Indian LAN Gaming Cup)
- Karate (Green belt Shūkōkai Karate)
- Solving Programming Problems (1st place in behind the Scene and InCanity in MuKTi '13 and 2nd place in Simplex in ANK '12)
- Playing Chess (3<sup>rd</sup>, 1<sup>st</sup> and 2<sup>nd</sup> position in Regional Sports meet in 2007,2006 and 2005. Hence went to Nationals 3 times)

# References

- Sahil Gandhi (sahilgandhi2011@gmail.com) Product Evangelist, Ameyo (previously known as Drishti-Soft Solutions).
- **Dr. Hausi Müller** (hausi@uvic.ca) Professor, University of Victoria.